lulus.com 2019-04-23

# Feel Safe Shopping Women's Clothing with Lulus Privacy Policy

Effective May 25, 2018

YOUR PRIVACY IS OUR PRIORITY

Only the Best

We use your data to give you  
the best shopping experience!

| 

Locked Up Tight

Your data is highly secure-  
we protect it like it's our own!  
  
---|---  
  
No Spam

You decide when and how you  
hear from us. Unsubscribe anytime!

| 

Clear Communication

Have a question about your data?  
We're happy to answer!  
  
_**Who We Are**_

This Privacy Policy is an agreement between you and Lulu’s Fashion Lounge, LLC, which is known as Lulus or Lulus.com. Along with our representatives, officers, shareholders, subsidiaries, affiliates, parents, employees, and agents (collectively “Lulus” or “we” or “us” or “our”), we provide our website, Lulus.com, to you subject to the following Policy. For our European Economic Area (“EEA”) customers, Lulu’s Fashion Lounge, LLC is the data controller – the company responsible for your personal information.

You may contact us regarding this policy by emailing [privacy@lulus.com](mailto:privacy@lulus.com) or through the mail: Lulus, attn: Privacy, 195 Humboldt Ave., Chico, CA 95928.

 _ **Who You Are**_

Under the Lulus Terms of Service, you must be at least 18 years old and not a person barred from receiving services under the laws of the United States or other applicable jurisdictions to use our website.

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not submit personal information to us or use the website.

 _ **Accepting This Privacy Policy**_

To provide you with services, including access to our website, we need to collect and process some information about you (your “personal information”). By using our website, you agree that we may do that in the ways described below. 

IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THESE TERMS FOR ANY REASON, YOU MAY SIMPLY STOP USING THE WEBSITE.

We may amend or change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Changes to the Privacy Policy will be posted to our website.

 _ **Information We Collect**_

To provide you with the full Lulus shopping experience, we collect and retrieve your personal information in a number of different ways. Why we collect your information and what we do with it depends on the type of information. The tables below provide more details.

 **YOUR NAME AND CONTACT DETAILS**

If you create a Lulus account or place an order with us, we collect your name and contact details, such as your email address, shipping addresses, and phone number.

Information Collected | Why?  
---|---  
Name | 

  * For shipment or billing details
  * To personalize your contact or website experiences
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or Lulus

Email | 

  * To send updates about your order
  * To contact you regarding issues around your order, experience, contests entered, or requested product information
  * To update you on items in your cart
  * To keep you up to date about Lulus products and promotions. We will only send you these emails with your permission, and you can unsubscribe at any time – just use the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any Lulus email
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or Lulus

Phone Number | 

  * To contact you for urgent issues surrounding your order
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or Lulus
  * To support you as a customer when requested

Shipping Address | 

  * To complete the shipment of your order
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or Lulus
  * To allow us to understand and improve the experience for users like you

**YOUR DATE OF BIRTH INFORMATION**

Information Collected | Why?  
---|---  
Birthday | 

  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or Lulus
  * To send a birthday gift, if you are subscribed to our promotional emails

Birth Year | 

  * To improve and personalize your shopping experience

**YOUR PAYMENT INFORMATION**

When you place an order, we require payment information on file. When you enter your payment information (credit card number, expiration date, and CVV code) it is sent directly to a secure third-party credit card processing center. Lulus does not store any direct credit card or 3rd party payment information. We do store billing addresses, generic payment type, and, if you opt in, the last four digits of your credit card for your convenience during the ordering process.

Information Collected | Why?  
---|---  
Billing Address | 

  * Our payment partners require this information to process an order
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or Lulus

Generic Payment Type | 

  * To give reference for support issues
  * To alert you when we detect or are verifying fraudulent activity
  * To allow us to understand and improve the experience for users like you

Last Four Digits of Credit Card | 

  * To provide convenience for you when you choose to order again

**YOUR CONTACT HISTORY WITH US**

What you’ve said to us — for example, over the phone, on email, or on live chat.

Information Collected | Why?  
---|---  
Email Correspondence | 

  * To respond to your requests to make sure you receive great customer service and ensure that any and all concerns or issues have been addressed
  * For a historic record of your contacts to save time during your inquiries
  * To ensure issues and questions you raised are proactively addressed for other customers 
  * To train our staff to ensure the best experience possible for all customers who contact us

Phone Correspondence | 

  * To respond to your requests to make sure you receive great customer service and ensure that any and all concerns or issues have been addressed
  * To train our staff to ensure the best experience possible for all customers who contact us

Live Chat Logs | 

  * To respond to your requests to make sure you receive great customer service and ensure that any and all concerns or issues have been addressed
  * For a historic record of your contacts to save time during your inquiries
  * To train our staff to ensure the best experience possible for all customers who contact us

Survey or Site Feedback | 

  * To respond to your requests to make sure you receive great customer service and ensure that any and all concerns or issues have been addressed 
  * To improve the experience for you and other users

**PURCHASE AND PRODUCT FEEDBACK HISTORY AND SAVED PRODUCTS**

What you’ve bought, what’s in your shopping cart, what’s on your wishlist, and your loves (favorite items you’ve identified by clicking the Lulus heart)

Information Collected | Why?  
---|---  
Purchased Items | 

  * To fulfill and ship your order as requested
  * To allow you to return and review delivered items
  * To tailor your experience around your interests
  * To improve our product selection and experience for you and other users
  * To help our buyers make sure we have the best items in stock for you and other customers
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or Lulus

Items Added to Your Cart | 

  * To allow your order to be completed smoothly when you’re ready to check out
  * To update you on items in your cart, including low quantity or sale status
  * To tailor your experience around your interests

Wishlist Items | 

  * To allow you to save, organize, recall, and share items you’ve selected
  * To allow us to personalize product recommendations toward your interests

Loved Items | 

  * To allow you quickly recall items and compare items you’ve selected
  * To allow us to personalize product recommendations towards your interests

Reviewed Items | 

  * To better inform other customers about the pros and cons of a product
  * To provide feedback on fit based on various physical attributes (eg: height, weight, body type, etc.)
  * To help others see what our clothing looks like in real life

**INFORMATION ABOUT YOUR DEVICE TYPE, AND HOW YOU USE OUR WEBSITE**

We automatically receive and record information from your browser or device when you visit our site, including your IP address and device type (i.e. computer, tablet, or smart phone), cookies, and data about which pages you visit. This information is stored in log files and is collected automatically. If you have an account with us, we may combine this information with other personal information we collect about you.

Information Collected | Why?  
---|---  
IP Address | 

  * To ensure the security of our website and determine, on an anonymous basis, where our customers are located
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or Lulus

Device Type | 

  * To improve the experience for you and other users like you
  * To resolve customer issues that center around devices, operating systems, or browsers used
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or Lulus and to keep your data secure

Page Visit History | 

  * To improve the experience for you and other users like you
  * To respond to and resolve any customer issues based on a specific page or page type

Identification Cookies | 

  * To provide you with Lulus advertising, including across your devices
  * To provide you with a personalized shopping experience and ensure our advertising is relevant to you

**SPECIFIC DETAILS ABOUT YOU**

You may enter some specific details about yourself to help other customers or for personalization towards yourself. We collect body information related to fit measurements and photographs for product representations. You can choose to enter your fit details (height, body type, weight, and measurements) in your profile or as part of leaving product reviews for other customers. There are two ways we might have your photographs: if you post a photo review or if you accepted our request to use your photo from a third-party site (like Instagram). We will never use your photograph without your express permission.

Information Collected | Why?  
---|---  
Uploaded Photos | 

  * To help other customers see what our clothing looks like on actual customers
  * To offer other customers the products and shopping experience most relevant to them
  * To showcase styling ideas and product fit from other customers

Your Fit Details | 

  * To help us better suggest products and sizes for you 
  * To help other customers better understand how products may fit them
  * To help our buyers keep the best items in stock for you and other customers
  * To help our customer service representatives guide you to the correct size

**YOUR PUBLIC REVIEWS AND BLOG COMMENTS**

We allow our customers to provide public feedback in the form of reviews about our website and comments on our blog posts. Please remember that any information that you disclose on public portions of the website, such as the reviews and blog comments, are not private and may be viewed (and potentially shared) on the Lulus website and beyond. Please use caution when deciding to disclose your personal information in the public portions of our website.

Information Collected | Why?  
---|---  
Site Review | 

  * To improve the experience for you and other users like you
  * To respond to your requests and ensure you receive great customer service

Blog Comments | 

  * To provide feedback based on your communications
  * To allow us to reference contest entries

**ANONYMOUS AGGREGATED INFORMATION**

We also receive anonymous and aggregated personal information through data analytics services. We use these analytics to ensure our website functions and to improve the Lulus shopping experience. These analytics services record information such as how often you visit Lulus.com, what actions you take on our website, aggregated usage, performance data, errors and debugging information, and how you got to our website. We do not link the information from our analytics services to any personal information that you submit to us.

 **OUR LEGAL BASES FOR COLLECTING AND PROCESSING YOUR INFORMATION**

When you access or use our website, we collect, use, and otherwise process your personal information as described in this policy. We rely on a number of legal bases to use your information:

  * As necessary to perform a contract with you or to take steps in preparation for a contract with you, including enabling you to make a purchase from us;
  * Because you have consented to the processing, such as for receiving marketing messages or third-party data sharing related to advertising;
  * As necessary to comply with a legal obligation, a court order, or to exercise or defend legal claims;
  * As necessary for the purposes of our or a third party’s legitimate interests;
  * As necessary to protect your vital interests, or those of others.

Here are some of our legitimate interests for collecting and processing your personal information:

Detecting and preventing fraud: We have a legitimate interest in detecting and preventing fraud. To do so, it is necessary that we collect and retain information about each transaction made at Lulus. Our auditors require that we keep this information so they can verify that all transactions recorded by Lulus were made by real customers. The credit card companies we work with require this information in the event that fraudulent charges are made using your credit card.

Providing access to and improving Lulus.com: We may use your information to improve and customize our website, including sharing of your information for such purposes, and this is necessary to pursue our legitimate interests of improving our website and our products. This is also necessary to enable us to pursue our legitimate interest in understanding how our website is being used, and to develop and expand our customer base. It is also necessary to allow us to pursue our legitimate interest in improving our website’s functionality and in obtaining insights into what our customers and potential customers want.

Providing access to and improving our customer service: We may use your information to provide you with customer service, and also to improve the service we provide to all customers. This is necessary for us to pursue our legitimate interest in providing great customer service.

Improving our product offerings: We may use your information to improve the products offered at Lulus, and to inform our buying team so they can provide you and our other customers with a great selection of products. This is necessary for us to pursue our legitimate interest in being your destination for affordable luxury.

Keeping our website and your data secure: We have a legitimate interest in ensuring the security of our website, including enhancing protection of our company and our customers against spam, harassment, intellectual property infringement, crime, and security risks of all kind.

 _ **Information We Share**_

Except as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy, we will not provide access to your personal information to third parties for any unauthorized purpose. We never sell or share your contact information to other companies for their direct marketing purposes.

Lulus works closely with third-party businesses (our “vendors”) for a variety of purposes, including assisting us to perform and improve the Lulus website, to deliver your orders, and to provide advertising and email services. These vendors include payment processors, research companies, and analytics and security providers. These third parties have only limited access to your information, and may use your information only to perform these tasks on our behalf. We take reasonable steps to require that any such vendor complies with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

It is necessary for us to share your information with some of our vendors in order to complete our contract with you; for example, to allow them to process payments and shipments and to help us keep our website secure. Other vendors help us improve our website and our products; for example, by helping us conduct research into how we could better serve our customers, or reach new customers. We have a legitimate interest in working with these vendors to improve our business. We rely on your consent (which can be withdrawn at any time) to send marketing messages and for third-party sharing relating to advertising.

Lulus also may share demographic information about our website visitors with vendors, but it will be aggregated and de-personalized, so personal information is not revealed.

Your information will remain subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy even if we undergo a business transition. However, we may transfer your information to a successor person or entity upon an acquisition or other corporate reorganization. You hereby consent to such transfers, and agree that we may assign and transfer all of the rights, benefits, duties, and obligations of this Privacy Policy to a successor person or entity.

We may also disclose your information if we have a good faith belief that we are required to do so by law or if acting with a good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to: (1) comply with legal process; (2) enforce this Policy or the Terms; (3) respond to legal claims; (4) respond to your requests for customer service or transaction completion; or (5) protect the rights, property or personal safety of Lulus, the website’s users or the public. In these cases, our use of your information may be necessary for the purposes of our or a third party’s legitimate interest in keeping our website secure, preventing harm or crime, enforcing or defending legal rights, or preventing damage. Such use may also be necessary to comply with a legal obligation, a court order, or to exercise or defend legal claims. It may also be necessary in the public interest (such as to prevent crime).

 _ **Consent, Control, Retention**_

Much of your information is stored in your Lulus account profile. You may change or correct the information in your account profile by clicking here or emailing [privacy@lulus.com](mailto:privacy@lulus.com). Only your first and last name and email address are required to have an account with Lulus. If you would like to cancel your account entirely, please email [privacy@lulus.com](mailto:privacy@lulus.com).

Depending on your location, such as the EEA or Canada, you may also have certain additional rights with respect to your information, such as: 

  1. a)data access and portability (including the right to obtain a copy of your personal data, some of which is available through your account profile);
  2. b) data correction (including the ability to update your personal data, much of which you can change directly using your account settings);
  3. c) data deletion (including the right to have Lulus delete your personal information, except information we are required by law to retain);
  4. d) withdrawal of consent (when we rely on your consent to process your information, such as for our marketing emails); and
  5. e) objection to processing (when our processing is based on legitimate interests; this includes, in limited circumstances, the right to ask Lulus to stop processing your personal data). 

If you are located in the EEA or Canada and would like a copy of your data, to have your data corrected, to have your data deleted, to withdraw consent to our further processing your information, or to object to our processing based on legitimate interests, please email [privacy@lulus.com](mailto:privacy@lulus.com) with your request and your country of residence.

Unless you are located in the EEA or Canada and have exercised one of your rights listed above, Lulus will retain your information for as long as is necessary for our legitimate business purposes. Lulus will always retain data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal and financial obligations (for example, to satisfy our auditors, to comply with applicable tax/revenue laws, to enforce our agreements, and as otherwise described in this policy).

Without prejudice to any other rights you may have, if you are located in the EEA or Canada, you have the right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection regulator.

 _ **Cookies and Advertising**_

When you visit Lulus.com we insert some instructions on your computer or mobile device. These instructions will be in the form of a “cookie” or similar file. Cookies are small pieces of instruction stored on your hard drive or device, not on our website. Cookies provide us with information that we use to enhance your experience on Lulus.com. Right now, there are two basic types of cookies. One is a session cookie which terminates when the user’s session ends. The second is a persistent cookie, which is a text file that remains stored on your computer for a period of time. Your Internet browser contains instructions about how to remove persistent cookies. If you reject all cookies, you may not be able to create or sign in to your account with us or otherwise take full advantage of the Lulus.com website.

We use cookies to collect information, on an aggregate basis, about how Lulus.com is used. This information includes the date and time of visits to Lulus.com and time spent on our website. We also use cookies to learn more about our audience size and usage patterns, to store information about your preferences to allow us to customize our website according to your interests and to provide a more personalized experience, to speed up searches or to recognize you when you return to our website, to identify the pages viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visits, page interaction information (such as click, scrolling, etc.) or methods used to browse away from a page, but none of our cookies is intended to identify you personally. You can obtain more information about cookies at <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>.

We may also use web beacons. A web beacon is an invisible graphic on a web page or email that is programmed to collect non-personally identifiable information about the use of a given website or newsletter, such as whether or not an email is opened and viewed.

We partner with third parties to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partners may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. These technologies allow a site to recognize your computer or mobile device each time you use Lulus.com. We rely on your consent to drop and read non-technically necessary cookies.

Some browsers have a “do not track” feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. At this time, we do not respond to browser “do not track” signals.

 **HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION**

We take commercially reasonable steps to safeguard and deter unauthorized access to your information. Lulus complies with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS). This means that when we collect or transmit sensitive information such as a credit or debit card number, we use industry standard methods to protect that information.

Although we take reasonable measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of your information, no e-commerce platform, website, electronic database or system is completely secure. 

**WHERE WE ARE LOCATED**

Lulus is located in the United States, and we primarily store your information in the United States. By using our website and/or providing us with information, you are agreeing to transfer and store your data in the United States.

To our international customers: the privacy laws and standards in the United States, including the level of protection applied to your data and the rights of authorities to access your personal information, may differ from those that apply in the country in which you reside. The European Commission has not made a determination that the United States adequately provides safeguards for the transfer of data, and at this time Lulus has not put in place the exact safeguards set forth in GDPR Article 46. The transfer of your data to the United States is necessary for the performance of our contract with you (so we can process your order) and/or to take pre-contractual measures at your request (i.e. to set up your Lulus account).

At times, we may transfer your personal information outside of the United States, in which case we take reasonable steps to make sure your personal information continues to be appropriately protected. However, no data transfer system is completely secure.

 _ **Third Party Websites**_

Lulus.com contains links to other websites. Other websites we link to include social platforms. We also use third-party plug-ins in certain places on our website. For example, when you click on an icon on the Lulus website to share our products on a third party social platform, you are also loading content from that third-party site. That site may request cookies directly from your browser. These interactions are subject to the privacy policy and terms of service of the third-party site, not ours. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such services. We do not make any representations regarding the policies or practices of third parties. When you use third-party sites or services, their own terms and privacy policies will govern your use of those sites or services. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of third parties before disclosing personal information to them. For the purposes of E.U. law, these third parties are independent controllers of data.

 _ **Your California Privacy Rights**_

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of Lulus who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personally identifiable information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. However, at this time we do not share any of your personally identifiable information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes.
